Guide to the Joseph R. Starobin and Robert S. Starobin Papers, 1945-1976
Department of Special Collections
Joseph R. Starobin and Robert S. Starobin Papers,
1945-1976
Special Collections M0675
Starobin, Joseph R.; Starobin, Robert S.
24 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased 1994.
Biography
Joseph R. Starobin (1913-1976) and his son, Robert S. Starobin (1939-1971) each played significant roles in the radical movements of their times, the so-called Old Left and New Left.
Joseph Starobin, born of a White Russian Jewish family in New York City, grew up among Socialists and became radicalized during the Great Depression. He was the foreign editor of the Daily Worker from 1945-1954, In 1951, on the Communist Party's suggestion, he went into to voluntary exile to escape McCarthyism. During this time, JS travelled widely in Latin America, France, Indochina, and China. Two books emerged out of these experiences: Paris to Peking and Eyewitness in Indo-China. JS was also in charge of the Communist Party USA's peace activities. JS entered the PhD. Program in history at Columbia University, and received his degree in Political Science. JS then taught at York University in Toronto. His dissertation was published as American Communism in Crisis: 1943-1957. JS's identification with the "Old Left" and academia thus provided a link with his son's leftist activity.
Robert Starobin was a "Red Diaper Baby," who was exposed to socialist politics early in life. He was influenced by his father, Joseph, and his mother, Norma, who was a dancer. He attended private progressive grade schools and graduated from the Bronx High School of Science in 1957. He attended Cornell for undergraduate studies, where he was editor of the student newspaper. Following college, he hitchhiked across the country to California, where he met and married Elsa within 3 weeks. He attended graduate school in history at UC Berkeley and participated in the Free Speech Movement, the SDS and the black power movement. His 1968 dissertation from UC Berkeley eventually became his major book, Industrial Slavery in the Old South, published in 1970. In 1966 RS joined the history faculty at the University of Wisconsin-Madison and became involved with reforming the history department and with student protest groups. He pioneered the first black studies course at UW-Madison in 1968. RS published articles and spoke on his research interests in black history and the black power movement, but by the end of the 1960s, he felt unaccepted by the Black Panthers and by black academics because he was white. His marriage with Elsa broke up and she moved back to California in 1968. In 1969, RS returned to Cornell for a post-doctoral fellowship and again became involved with protest groups on campus. At the end of the year, he resigned from UW-Madison and accepted a teaching position at SUNY-Binghampton. He committed suicide in 1971.
Scope and Content
The Joseph and Robert Starobin Collection consists of 47 archival boxes, some of which are oversized. The collection contains personal papers and research materials of the Starobin father and son. There are 17 boxes of periodical publications reflecting their political and research interests. More personal letters and the libraries of each man are housed at Wisconsin State Historical Society.
The collection is organized into 3 series: Joseph Starobin (JS), Robert Starobin (RS), and Serials. Series I and II are arranged roughly by the following topics: Personal life; Academic life and research; Clippings, periodicals, and pamphlets; and Whole newspapers. JS primarily contains clippings on the US Communist Party and the international communist and socialist movements from the 1940s-60s. RS is the larger series and includes his research notes on American slavery, as well as materials on African-American issues and the Black Power movement, the war in Vietnam, New Left politics, and student protest groups in the 1960s. It also contains a collection of 1960s-era radical newspapers. Serials contains academic, political, critical, and popular journals from the 1940s-1970s. They are arranged alphabetically by title.
Arrangement Note
Joseph Starobin and Robert Starobin materials separated. Arranged by subject within series. Periodicals arranged alphabetically.
Access Terms
Starobin, Joseph Robert, 1913-1976.; Starobin, Robert S., 1939-1971.; Browder, Earl, 1891-1973.; Beichman, Arnold.; Civil rights and socialism.; New Left--United States.; Radicalism.; Social movements.; Socialism--United States.; Communists--United States. lcsh; Communism.; Communist parties--United States.; Afro-Americans--Race identity.; Afro-Americans--Social conditions.; Civil rights movements--United States.; Socialists. lcsh; The Daily Worker.
Container List
- Series I: Joseph Starobin
  - Subseries 1: Personal life
    - Columbia University application materials (Box 1, Folder 1)
      (biographical info)
    - letter of sympathy after Robert's suicide (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Christmas cards, 1971 (Robert's suicide) 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Christmas cards, 1971 (Robert's suicide) 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Berkshire Forum (from folder marked "Norma to answer) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Berkshire Forum (from folder marked "Norma to answer) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Berkshire Forum (from folder marked "Norma to answer) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Berkshire Forum (from folder marked "Norma to answer) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Highlander, house in Provincetown, MA (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Holiday music (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Event programs (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Event programs (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Travel (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Travel (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Travel (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Stenographer's notebook (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Collection of stamps from USSR (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 2: Academic Life and Research
    - Joseph R. Starobin. Eyewitness in Indo-China. NY: Greenwood Publishers, 1968., 2 copies. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Joseph R. Starobin. Paris to Peking. NY:Cameron Associates, Inc. 1955., 2 photocopies. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Articles by JS, various publications: (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - - "Why the Paris peace talks have been fruitless" - The Times, London, 8/3/70
    - - "The American Left and the Dilemmas of the Cold War" - For AHA panel. 12/29/69.
    - See Box 2, folder 8
    - - "How a York University professor tried to end the war in Vietnam" - Toronto Daily Star, 11/29/69.
    - Articles by JS, various publications: (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - - "What will US do about Viet Cong peace moves?" - Globe and Mail (Canada) 10/7/70
    - - "Post Continentalism: an American radical view" -Canadian Forum, 4-5/70
    - - "Isn't Canada Missing the Chance to be different?" - Franternally Yours, 12/70
    - Article by JS: "Communism in Western Europe." Reprint from Foreign Affairs, Oct. 1965., 2 copies. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Article by JS: "Toward a Socialist Revival" - The American Socialist, March 1957. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Review by JS: "World Economy, a review by Joseph Starobin" - New World Review, Oct. 1956. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - "Notes on a Visit to Latin America" by JS, typewritten impressions taken during an "unofficial visit to 7 independent nat'ns of Latin America and several of the Caribbean islands during the months of June and July of [1947]." 1947 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Series of articles (1-10) by JS in El Siglo, Mexico. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Publications mentioning JS and his work. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Program from AHA 84th Annual Meeting. 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - JS gave paper "The American Left and the Dilemmas of the Cold War, 1945-1952" p. 117., 2 copies.
      See Box 2, folder 3
  - Subseries 3: Clippings, periodicals, pamphlets
    - Scrapbook "Earl Browder" (Box 3(OS), Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook "Earl Browder" Apr.-June 1946 (Box 3(OS), Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook Dec. 1945-Apr. 1946 (Box 3(OS), Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook April-Oct. 1946 (Box 3(OS), Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook Nov. 1946-Feb. 18, 1947 (Box 3(OS), Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook Feb. 18, 1947 (Box 3(OS), Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook Feb.-March 1947 (Box 3(OS), Folder 7)
    - "Strike" clippings (Box 3(OS), Folder 8)
    - "Strike" clippings (Box 3(OS), Folder 9)
    - AIMS newsletter (American Institute for Marxist Studies), V ol. I:1- Vol. II:6 (Box 3(OS), Folder 10)
    - Communism materials: (Box 3(OS), Folder 11)
      - "Statement of Policy and Purpose" - 1958
      - Independent-Socialist Party, 1958 NY elections
      - Statement from the Communist Party of Italy "Project for Study of U.S. Finance Capital," by Victor Perlo.
    - Communism materialls: Amendments to Draft Resolution c. 1956 (Box 3(OS), Folder 12)
    - "Constitution of the Communist Party USA 1957 (Box 3(OS), Folder 13)
    - Communism clippings 1940s-50s (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Communism clippings 1940s-50s (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Communism clippings 1940s-50s (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Communism clippings 1940s-60s (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Communism clippings 1944-46 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Communism clippings 1944-46 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Communism clippings 1944-47 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Communism clippings (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Communism clippings (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Communism clippings (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Communism clippings (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Communism clippings (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Communism clippings (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Clippings from Daily Worker, New Leader (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Clippings from Daily Worker, New Leader (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Clippings from Daily Worker, New Leader (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Clippings from Daily Worker, New Leader (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Clippings from Daily Worker, New Leader (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - China clippings (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - China clippings (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Communism materials. Includes clippings and notes as well as the following: (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - - "Draft Resolution for the 16th National Convention of the Communist Party, USA. Adopted Sept. 13, 1956," Political Affairs Pamphlet. NY: New Century Publishers, 1956.
    - - "The Walter-McCarran Law, Police State Terror against Foreign-Born Americans," Abner Green. NY: New Century Publishers, 1953."
    - - "Statement by J.Edgar Hoover ... An Analysis of the Sixteenth Annual Convention of the Communist Party of the United States." 1957 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - - "The 16th Convention of the Communist Party, U. S. A. - Interim Report of the Subcommittee to Investigate the Administration of the Internal Security Act and other Internal Security Laws." Washington: GPO, 1957. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper with article "Economic problems of socialism in the USSR" by Joseph Stalin., Poor condition. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 1954-57, 1957 CP Convention, Arnold Beichman 1954-57 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 1954-57, 1957 CP Convention, Arnold Beichman 1954-57 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 1954-57, 1957 CP Convention, Arnold Beichman 1954-57 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 1954-57, 1957 CP Convention, Arnold Beichman 1954-57 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Earl Browder: (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 1936 Presidential Campaign, questions from audience. 1936
    - "American Communist Party in the 1930's." 1966
    - CIO materials (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "Communist Theory and the American Negro Question" by Van Zanten., Photocopy of article. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "How Elastic is a Communist?" Feature in Fortune. 1957
    - "Elements of Marxism"- syllabus.
    - "Reason of State" - Walter Millis. 1958
    - "Proposal Concerning the General Line of the International Communist Party Movement.", Photocopy, poor condition. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "Current Economic Developments in Europe," author unknown. Typed pre-publication article. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - New Republic articles. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "Implications of World Leadership," John J. McCloy. Stearns Lecture at Phillips Academy. 1954 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - "Thesis, Antithesis and Synthesis: The World's Hope" - A. L. Fletcher.
    - 2 different incomplete unsigned manuscripts. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "New Dimensions for American Foreign Operations,"Harvey Williams. Keynote address, 2nd Annual Special Conference on Foreign Operations of the International Management Association, 1957. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Reviews of The Long Journey, George Charney. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - World Strength of the Communist Party, Organizations 18th Annual Report. US Department of State, Bureau of Intelligence and Research. Jan. 1966 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - East of Suez. Report by John Scott. 1956 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - "What is Science?" by Hans Freistadt. Article reprint from The American Socialist, 1957. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Clippings (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - China and Southeast Asia
      - JS notes (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - "Documents on the Sino-Soviet Dispute, the Chinese Side." Bibliography., Photocopy. (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - "Mao Tse-Tung's Revolutionary Strategy and Peking's International Behavior." Tang Tsou and Morton Halperin, 1965. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - "Chinese Communist Response to Alternative US Active and Passive Defense Postures." Davis B.Bobrow. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - "Wang Chieh - (Chairman Mao's Good Soldier)." B. Michael Frolic. (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Peking People's Daily. 1962 Dec. 31 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Statement of A. Doak Report, US Senate Committee on Foreign Relations. 1956 Mar. 8 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Institute of Pacific Relations publications (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - China Pamphlets (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Publications (Box 6, Folder 10)
        - - "Ten-Year Report of the Director." Harvard 1965
        - University East Asia Research Center.
        - - "Sources of Chinese Communist Conduct," Howard L. Boorman. School of International Affairs, Columbia University.
      - - "The Sino-Soviet Dispute and Asian Communism." Donald Zagoria. School of International Affairs, Columbia University. (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Publications (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - - Quakers Visit China. Prepared by the members of the British Quaker Mission to the People's
      - Republic of China. (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - - Report from China. Hugh Handyman.
      - - Mao Tse-Tung as Historian. Howard L. Boorman. Reprinted from China Quarterly. 1966 Oct.-Dec.
      - Preliminary Prospectus. "Men and Politics in Republican China, a Biographical Dictionary. (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Reports (Box 6, Folder 13)
        - - "China's Yezhovchina." Christian Duval. 1966
        - Radio Liberty Research Paper, 1966.
        - - "Daily Report - Communist China." Foreign Broadcast Information Service, 1968.
      - - "China's Strategy, a Critique." Donald A. Zagoria. Commentary Report, 1965. (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Reports (Box 6, Folder 14)
        - - "Communique on Talks between Chinese and Burmese Premiers and other Documents." Supplement to People's China, 1955.
        - - "Report on the First Five-Year Plan for Development of the National Economy." Li Fu-Chun. Supplement to People's China, 1955.
      - Publications (Box 6, Folder 15)
        - - "The Language Report on China." James D. White. Saturday Review, March 17, 1956.
        - - "International Affairs Reports from Quaker Workers," III: 1, 1956.
        - - Peking Review 40, 1969. 1969
      - Publications (Box 6, Folder 16)
        - - "China: Cultural Revolution of Counter-
        - Revolutionary Coup." Wang Ming. Issued by Communist Party, USA.
      - 2 books in Chinese: one of accounts, one of sketches. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Publications of the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - "Report of the President 1958-59" 1958-59
      - "Report of the President 1959-60" 1959-60
      - "Bulletin on the Fund for the Republic" 1959 Feb.
    - Publications of the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - "Community of Fear" by Harrison Brown and James Real 1961
      - "Corporation and the Republic" by Scott Buchanan 1958
      - "Demilitarized World..." by Walter Millis 1964
      - "Labor looks at Labor" by members of the UAW 1963
    - "The Police" Interview by Donald McDonald with William H. Parker. 1962 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - "World Without War" by Walter Millis 1961
    - Publications of the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. Occasional papers: (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - "Broadcasting and Government Regulation in a Free Society" 1959
      - "Ethics and the Politician" 1960
      - Tragedy and the New Politics" 1960
      - "The U.S. and Revolution" 1961
      - "The U.S., Cuba, and Latin America" 1961
      - "Civilization, Industrial Society, and Love" 1961
      - "Bureaucracy and the Forests" 1962
    - Publications of the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions Occasional Papers: (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - "Science, Scientists, and Politics" - Robert M. Hutchins, Scott Buchanan, Donald N. Michael, Chalmers Sherwin, James Real, Lynn White, Jr. 1963
      - "Science and Peace" - Linus Pauling 1964
      - "The Arts in a Democratic Society" - G. Phillips 1966
    - Publications of the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions "Peace on Earth" Occasional Papers: (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - "On Coexistence", 1965
      - "Peace on Earth, a Sampling of the Press Record" 1965
      - "On the Developed and the Developing" 1965
      - "On the World Community" 1965
    - Publications of the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. Occasional Papers: (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - "ABM: Yes or NO?" -Center Occasional Paper 1969
      - "Center Report" Vol. IV, 1 1970
    - Publications of the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Center Diary: 10 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      1966 Jan.
      - Center Diary: 17 1967 Mar.-Apr.
    - Publications of the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Center Diary: 18 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      1967 May-June
      - Center Magazine, I:5 1968 July
    - Center Magazine, II:1 1969 Jan. (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Center Magazine, II:2 1969 March
    - Reprints from the Harvard Business Review (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - "Religious Foundations of Economic Progress" -Kenneth E. Boulding 1952 May-June
      - "Business Leadership and a Creative Society" - Abram T. Collier 1953 Jan.-Feb.
      - "Skyhooks" - O.A. Ohmann 1955 May-June
      - "Business and the Good Society" - Raphael Demos 1955 July-Aug.
      - "Can the Businessman Apply Christianity" - Harold L. Johnson 1957 Sept.-Oct.
      - "Thinking Ahead" - Robert P. Ulin 1958 Jan.-Feb.
    - "Diagnosis of Management Problems" - Edward T.P. Watson 1958 Jan.-Feb. (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - "Watch Your Expense Accounts" - Henry Cassorte Smith 1958 Jan.-Feb.
    - Reprints of the Institute of Industrial Relations, UC Berkeley (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - "Some Social Reqisites of Democracy: Economic Development and Political Legitimacy"-S.M. Lipset 1959
      - "Democracy and Working-Class Authoritarianism" - S.M. Lipset 1959
      - "Industrialization, Ideologies, and Social Structure" - Reinhard Bendix 1959
    - Publications of the Institute of Industrial Relations, UC Berkeley (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - "Social Stratification and 'Right-Wing' Extremism" - S.M. Lipset 1960
      - "Structure of Enterprise in the 19th Century: The Cases of Britain and Germany" - D. Landes 1960
      - "Changing Social Structures" - Clark Kerr 1961
    - Occasional Papers from School of International Affairs, Columbia University:
      - "America in the Technetronic Age" - Z. Brzezinski 1967 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - "Peaceful Engagement in Europe's Future" - Z. Brzezinski 1965 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - "The True Story of Bo McJumper and his Hodag"- Fred and Mary Blair 'Holiday Greetings' 1956 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - "A Collection of Editorials and Resolutions in Opposition to the Un-American Activities Committee" c1960 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - "Analysis of Layoff, Recall, and Work-Sharing Procedures in Union Contracts" - US Dept. of Labor, Bulletin 1209 1957 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - "Survey of Current Business" - US Dept. of Commerce (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Pamphlets (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - "Some themes of Counter-Subversion..." - David Brion Davis 1960
      - "We Accuse McCarthyism" - Youth Labor League 1954
      - "The Story of a Congregation..."
      - "Where do We Go From Here? - an examination of the record of the 14th National Convention CPUSA" - 'Americus' 1948
    - Pamphlets (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - "The US and Vietnam: 1944-1947" - Prepared for the use of the Committee on Foreign Relations, US Senate 1972
      - "The Human Cost of Communism in China" - Prepared at the request of the Committee on the Judiciary US Senate 1971
    - Pamphlets (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - "Scope of Soviet Activity in the US" - Hearing Committee on the Judiciary US Senate 1957
      - "Excerpts from Eighth Annual Report 1952-1953"- International Bank for Reconstruction and Development 1953
      - "Constitution of The UN Correspondents Association, as amended July 25, 1957." 1957
    - Pamphlets (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - "The Greeks have a word for it: ENOSIS" - Thomas Anthem
      - "Behind the Bars for the First Amendment"- Committee of First Amendment Defendants c 1960
      - "The Educational System of the Soviet Union" - Elizabeth Moos 1950
      - "Notes on the Foreign Situation Based on a Trip Abroad" - Ernest T. Weir. 1953
      - "The United States and Latin America..." - Alexander Wiley. 1953
    - Pamphlets (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - "With Justice and Food for All" - M. Lincoln c 1956
      - "Statistical Bulletin, Metropolitan Life Insurance Company" 1958 Apr.
      - "City College Alumnus" 1957 Oct.
      - "1960 Preview" - H. Manchester 1955
      - "A Look at 1958: the Pulsebeat of Industry" 1958
    - Pamphlets (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - **Removed from collection** "Farm Tenancy - Report of President's Committee" 1937 Feb.
      - "Are we on the road to war?" - Leo Szilard 1961 Dec.
    - Pamphlets (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - "Pan-American Vocabulary"
      - "Know the Navajo" - Sandy Hassell 1961
      - "Official Guide Book to Diego Rivera's Frescoes in ..." 1963
    - Pamphlets (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - "Selections from Union Now" - C. K. Strait
      - "The Rise and Fall of Earl Browder" - Philip 1972
      - J. Jaffe (Reprint from Survey, Spr. 1972)
      - "What is Philosophy? Selected Readings" - Jefferson School of Social Science, NYC
    - Pamphlets (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - "The Diary of General Grow..." 1952
      - "Grasp the Weapon of Culture!" - V.J. Jerome 1951
      - "The American Mind..." - B. Liber, MD 1948
    - Italian Newspapers and Pamphlets (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Politica (Italy), 3 issues 1965
      - "Contro il 'Generale Peste'..." 1952
    - French Pamphlets (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - "Le Bureau National de l'Union des Etudiants 1965
      - Communistes écrit au Comité Central du Parti Communiste Français" - Unir
      - "la cinquième colonne la voici!" 1951
      - "Vive la Commune!"
    - French Pamphlets (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - "Le Mouvement mondial de la paix" c1951
      - "Les travaux de la cinquième session de l'Assemblé générale des Nations Unies" 1951
      - "La Documentation française, catalogue générale"
    - German Pamphlets (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - "USA in Wort und Bild - Cowboys in Paris" 1953
      - Clippings on student strikes 1960s
    - Polish Pamphlets (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - "The 6-Year Plan of economic development and building the foundations of Socialism in Poland" 1950
      - "Poland in the camp of peace" 1950
      - "Poland of Today" 1950
  - Subseries 4: Joseph Starobin's whole newspapers. Stored in flat print boxes.